# Charlie Rick

### Curriculum Vitae

www.charick.co.uk

M 07525 788 443 E charick@me.com A 33 Bedford Road, Laindon, Essex SS15 6PG

I have 5 years of experience in design roles. I'm now combining my design skills with my passion for IT to pursue a career as a developer. I have completed a self-funded technical training course and am looking for a Junior Developer role. My aim is to be a complex problem solver and continuously evolve as a developer.

# Experience

#### S6 Design & Print Designer/IT Admin

May 2016 - June 2018

- Set up and maintenance of hardware and network for an industrial printing operation.
- Project management of commercial projects.
- Research & analysis of new software and hardware to improve business productivity.
- Chose and assembled PC components to create machines that met performance requirements.
- Working collaboratively with colleagues to overcome challenges.
- Communication with high profile clients such as Monster Energy, Michelin and Xquisite PR.
- Build and upkeep of company websites, created CMS for easy blog updates.
- Design of branding, graphics and marketing materials.
- Troubleshooting issues that arose with hardware/software. Competent with Windows/Mac OS, Adobe CC Apps, RIP Software and wide format printer installations/repairs.

#### Essex Business & Leisure Designer

August 2013 - April 2016

- Responsible for the design, production & distribution of 55,000 publications each month.
- Effective planning & organisation to ensure all publications were finalised before deadlines.
- Interpersonal skills for building rapport with clients, forming professional relationships.
- Problem solving design, software and production challenges.

## Education

#### Just IT

June 2018 - August 2018

Self-funded technical training course which specialised in the coding fundamentals as well as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, API usage, C#, ASP.NET, MVC Concepts and SQL.

### Woodlands School, Basildon GCSE & Diploma

September 2008 - July 2013

English Literature  $B \mid$  English Language  $C \mid$  Maths  $B \mid$  Biology  $C \mid$  Chemistry  $C \mid$  Physics  $C \mid$  Geography  $C \mid$  German  $C \mid$  Music  $B \mid$  IT Level 2 Credit (Equivalent to two  $B \mid$  grade GCSEs)

Skills	Core skills are in <b>Bold</b>	Interests
--------	--------------------------------	-----------

HTML	jQuery	Computing From	
CSS	Git	interest in IT. I've alwa learning more a	
JavaScript	C#		
Vue.js	AJAX	<b>Music</b> I'm passio go to gigs. I'm also a g	
Sass	SQL	reg	
Bootstrap	Adobe CC Suite		

Computing From a very young age, I've had a keen interest in IT. I've always been an avid gamer & enjoyed learning more about hardware and new software.

**Music** I'm passionate about live music, I frequently go to gigs. I'm also a guitarist in a band with my friends, regularly playing gigs across London.